Hi, in this lesson I want to talk with you about chat context.
I will explain what is this, why we need to use it in how it helps to get better responses
from AI.
So context is all information we provide to AI models during core generation.
It might include files, symbols, folders and conversation history.
If it's clear what is files and folders, conversation history, you might ask what is
symbols.
If I open any file, you will see the name of the class, the constructor, the name of the
methods, a format currency, convert, save to history, it's all as symbols.
So symbols, it's methods, class names, variables and etc.
So the easiest way to provide explicit context is with this button or you can just type
the same symbol right here in a chat and you will see the drop down where you can choose
type of context you want to use.
So this is a great way to know specifically what file, folder or piece of code you will change
because the more specific you be, the better answer you will get from AI.
And if you see, let's talk about files and folders.
For example, you can reference entire files in chat by mentioning them right here.
And the story provides, you follow these files when generating the answers.
You can also drag and drop these files right here to the sidebar or if I just drag and
drop you see they edit as a context.
If you want to use folders, so you can choose folders like I don't have any folder right
here, I have the whole folder of the project, I can mention it.
And for example, if you need to choose, for example, the shooting folders, let's create
some source folder, some, I know, other utils and create just file util.js.
And let's try to mention like if I use source, I will type it, I will type source.
If I want to go to the Julian file, I just type the slash and I can choose utils and when
I type course or highlight what folders I have, so I can choose it.
Okay.
You also see when I've been typing the folder names, we have an option enable full context
in settings.
This is an option I talk you in one of the previous or last time that you can include
full context and for example, when it's enabled, corsard tries to include all files from
the folder as the context.
It might be used if you really need to consider all files in the folder as the context
because the downside of this option as, for example, models have some limitations.
How context big can be?
For example, how many symbols you can send them to the as a context?
And if you have this option enabled by default, you will use really a lot of tokens, tokens
it's like some symbols you send to the models, they have some rate limits and you will
see this tokens much faster.
So, I not recommend you to enable every time only if you own a proper one or in some higher
plans where you have a lot of really big rate limits and you really need to consider it
as a context.
I recommend you to explicitly mention files you need to use.
For example, also if you really need a big context, you can include this on.
You can also use, for example, Max mode for your model and in this case, you can include
the bigger context, but you of course you use much more tokens.
And also, every time you send a message, you might check how much tokens you send, for
example, I will ask both currencies, my app, the port, so after it will answer, I can
check how many tokens I used, so see, generate responses a bit longer, okay, it's quite
long.
I will stop it, so, but there are 2T pride here, you can hover it and see how many tokens
you use.
Also, there are another symbol quote you can use, or I will remove all the context, you
can mention a quote right here, and you can select some specific parts of quote which
you want to use, so, for example, I don't have many, if you have a bigger application,
you will see the difference, but currently, it suggests me only some parts of line you
see from 65 to 60, so, from 1 to 57, so, this is a class implementation, this is a class,
our user class name, okay, also, there is a docs symbol, so you can mention any doc,
the documentation, we can use, so, we can use any documentation, like if you know your
question is about the nexus, you can access right here, docs, access, so, and you will
use this documentation, if you need, you can add any documentation right here, you can
just mention the URL of the documentation, if it's not listed, so, and it will go through
the documentation, and when you ask some questions, you can also consider some sub pages,
so, it's really useful, okay, you can also use past shots, for example, if you are working
on a complex task, and you might need to reference context or some decisions from your
previous conversations, and, like, normally, when you need it, like, when you have a lot
of discussion with important context reference, so, when you start in a new task, and you
want to continue on the previous one, for example, you can use this previous shot as a context,
another symbol you can use is linear errors, when you mention it, and you have any linear
errors, like, you have some wrong formatting, you code, like, let me show you, for example,
I forget to paste comma, I have a literal, so, and I can mention it, what errors I have,
so, let's wait, you have a syntax error, so, and it's just me how I can fix it, I can
apply it right from here, and accept it, so, this is the most popular symbol, you can, of
course, use a different, the rest of the symbols, you can read about them in the commentation,
and I really hope this lesson give you much more information about context, and you'll
help you to be more clear in your prompts, and to really get better responses from AI, so,
let's see you in the next lesson, hi, I would love to hear, what do you think about this
course, I really hope you enjoy, and just want to say, your thoughts are very important
to me, if you have a moment, let's show your feedback and experience, believe in a review,
in case you have any questions, feel free to ask them in Q&A section, anytime, and see you
in the course.